



I am a frontend developer who loves using code to engage people. I have worn many hats in my career, and finding the right tool for the job when solving hard problems in the ever-changing frontend world is what I do best. Whether it's calculating the perfect bezier curve for an eye-catching animation or streamlining team processes through modular component libraries, my enthusiasm for crafting great user experience through frontend best practices and passion for experimentation runs deep.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Dwolla, Des Moines, IA (Remote from Kansas City, MO)

March 2014 to August 2016

Dwolla is transforming e-commerce by transitioning traditional plastic card-based transactions into direct - connect systems that save users money. As part of the frontend development team, I worked to enhance user interface and streamline the way people move millions of dollars with Dwolla each and every day. At Dwolla, I provided leadership for technical frontend development, including unit testing, validation, and other best practices of web applications.

- Pioneered JavaScript unit testing and maintenance within the team and made it an essential part of the deployment process.
- Sped up dwolla.com by implementing automated tasks to minify, compress, cache-control, and combine front end assets, as well as developed a tool to constantly monitor and assess page speed throughout the site.
- Built internal data monitoring tools using Node.js, D3.js, and React.js
- Established documentation for frontend standards by use of exemplars, react component libraries, and the development of extensible and adaptable style tiles.
- Managed frontend code quality through pull request reviews, third-party validation, semantic markup reviews, and by establishing processes for the service-side development team to understand the intricacies of browser testing.

Interactive Web Developer Platform Lead

MMGY Global, Kansas City, MO

June 2011 to March 2014

MMGY Global is the largest and most integrated travel marketing firm in the world. Their mission is simple: help travel companies grow revenue by motivating their customers. At MMGY, I was an expert interface developer leading an interdisciplinary team of interactive developers. Together, we conceptualized, created, produced, and extended overall brand and design direction online. On a day-to-day basis, I constantly pushed for innovation and excellence within the company by mentoring junior developers, introducing new technologies, and reimagining ways to communicate.

- Developed, maintained, and led the ramp up into responsive website creation that continually evolves to utilize new web technology trends.
- Key player in our laboratory team which discovers new technologies, new uses for existing technologies including microcontrollers like Arduino, and invents ways to apply these practices to our clientele.
- Stream-lined workflow and reorganized the development process to enhance work sharing, improve interdisciplinary collaboration, and increase profitability.
- Direct collaboration with Art Directors, Copywriters, Designers and other Developers to ensure best practices for optimized web performance and memorable end-user experience.
- Internal coordination with sales, project managers, and project staff to develop budgets, timelines, storyboards, and risk projections associated with advanced multimedia applications and animation.
- Performed code reviews and provided technical guidance for team members and junior developers.

MultiMedia Director

Salva O'Renick, Kansas City, MO

July 2005 to 2011

Salva O'Renick is a sales and marketing communications firm with a strong focus on financial and animal health clientele. At Salva O'Renick, I spearheaded all project responsibilities covering motion and audio, working primarily with Flash content for the web. In order to provide rich media solutions for our clients, it was necessary that I maintain a deep technical knowledge of web animation techniques, applications, and languages, such as Actionscript. My technical capabilities allowed me to develop cutting-edge, resellable applications that revolutionized how Salva O'Renick produced and marketed video and interactive animation.

Graphic Designer

Image Technologies Corporation, Kansas City, MO

December 2000 to July 2005

ITC is a full resource production company that specializes in all technical and promotional aspects of large corporate meetings and conventions. Their client base includes: Cerner, Ford Motor Company, Hallmark Cards, and Sprint. At ITC, I single-handedly built and operated a client-based graphic design department from the ground up, including multimedia and creative video production. Additionally, I introduced the use of 3D graphics modeling to pitch detailed set designs to clients through the use of Autodesk Maya. My responsibilities included extensive use of production equipment, development of client newsletter's and email templates, and design of client websites.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Studio Art - Photograpy/Graphic Design

University of Missouri Kansas City - Awarded 2003.

Bachelor of Arts in Communications - Mass Media

University of Missouri Kansas City - Awarded 2003.

Associate of Arts

Metropolitan Community Colleges, Lees Summit, Missouri - Awarded 2001.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE BASE

- Object oriented programming concepts and coding, primarily with JavaScript.
- Agile Development practices and knowledge to develop clean, refactored, and reusable code.
- Web languages and communication, such as JavaScript, Node, Angular.js, React.js, HTML and CSS.
- Web Development from conceptualization, design, front-end development and backend-development.
- I Utilization of efficient tools such as Git, Grunt, Sass, React.js on a day to day basis.
- Use and development of fully robust content management systems.
- Linux web server barebones setup, optimization, and automated deployment.
- Adobe products: Flash, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere, and Audition.
- Computer hardware modification and trouble shooting from both low and high levels.
- Production and post-production equipment and processing for video production and photography for professional client-based projects with small teams.
- Dabbler in microcontroller and microcomputer technology prototyping using Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Beaglebone, and electronic and mechanical components.

References furnished upon request